Now I'm going to show you how to prepare your frame to create your aged frames.
All the frames that you buy that are stained will have a more or less glossy finish on them.
To avoid having to use a primer on this particular project all you need to do is take a medium sandpaper.
I think this one is number 5.
Anyway you just take it and you just sand the areas that you're going to be painting.
And it's okay if you sand some of that paint off because you're base coat will take care of that.
Just make sure that you sand anywhere that it's still shiny just to give you an idea of how this goes.
And again, something like this you have a lot more detail to work with.
That's another thing you might want to keep in mind.
If you need to sand something like the other frame with the pewter you might want to mask off any off the molding that you do not want sanded and then just proceed to sand and rough up the surface.
Once that's done you just take, a damp paper towel is fine, and just lightly brush it all off to get off the sand that you just created.
The varnish and the dirt and that type of thing.
Because you don't want that mixed into your paint.
So you just make sure that you wipe all of the grooves off like this so it's clean everywhere that you're going to paint.
And then let it dry for a few minutes.
You can wipe it off to get any extra moisture.
But then you might want to wait just a few minutes for that to completely dry before you paint.